My first sock here is my sclera.
The second layer is the uvea, made up of the choroid, the iris, and the
ciliary body.
I remove that, and then I am left with the retina,
which consists primarily of two main layers,
the outer retina and the inner retina.
This is where the detachment occurs, where we have the moment of the primitive optic cup
coming in like this, making the right connection.
with the epiblast
of the surface that will
thicken, creating the
outer optic placode, which is
held here, growing around it.
This creates the primitive depression.
Then it will
be integrated like this.
We have the meeting
of this retina wrapping around
and this is where it will create what we call
the outer retina and the retina
interior. This is where you have the detachment
of the retina. There are people who have a detachment.
00:01:00.854
of the retina. You've probably heard of that. This is where it actually happens. And the retina,
if you look at it, is really brain, ventricular tissue.